Farshad Fahimi | .NET Full-Stack Developer

FarshadFahimi5@gmail.com | +98-910-4544-127 | Iran - Tehran | LinkedIn: Farshad Fahimi

Summary

A .NET/C# Developer with 6 years of experience in development and designing more than 6 web application and web APIs for reputable companies. Experienced with N-layer, Clean-Architecture and Micro-Service architectures. Someone with a great passion for learning what he doesn't know.

Work History

Full Stack Developer at Tehran Payment

October, 2022 - Present

- Redesigned of components for cleaner code that results 50% improvement.
- Accelerated overall system performance by 40% applying REDIS as in-memory cache.
- Learned Angular 14 and TypeScript to increase front-end development.
- o Refactored some parts of code with OOP and Solid concepts, resulted in less lines of code.
- o Planned and engineered RESTful web APIs with .NET core 6 and swagger Open-API.

Backend-Developer at Romaak Ertebat Co

March, 2022 - Present as part time

- Launched 4 Web APIs for different businesses with good maintainability.
- Used Redis cache to achieve boost performance up to 40%.
- o Pushed live data to client-side application with Hangfire Jobs and SignalR
- o Designed Web APIs for MCI company to visualize their live transaction logs.
- o Provided effective troubleshooting, debugging and remediation for NGDIR Web APIs.
- Used .NET Core 6, Clean Architecture, JWT to design and develop new Web APIs

Backend Developer at Next BTS

June, 2020 - March, 2022

- o Developed an application for dialysis centers to reduce red tape by 100%
- o Implemented some key features to make a program user-friendly.
- Effectively translated client requirements into complete application design, from database to project architecture, and system requirements.
- Used N-layer architecture, .NET Core 3 to communicate with third-party insurance companies web services.
- Built and maintained ASP.NET MVC web application

Self-Employed as Freelancer

October, 2018 - June 2020

Skills

C#, CQRS, REST Full Web API, JWT, OIDC, OOP, Database Design, ASP. Net MVC, Docker, ASP. Net Core v2+, Git, Git-Flow, TFS Entity Framework, EF Core, Agile Methodology, DDD, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Microservice, JavaScript, jQuery Solid, Angular v14, Design-Patterns, TypeScript

Education

Bachelor of Science - Sep 2012 - Aug 2017 | Tehran East University | Tehran, Iran | Computer Engineering

Languages

English - upper intermediate (Well reading, good understanding in communications)